<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Culture of Insight</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Culture of Insight</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018 Culture of Insight. All Rights Reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 20 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Automated Data Reports with R</title>
      <link>/blog/2018/08/20/2018-08-20-automated-data-reports-with-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2018/08/20/2018-08-20-automated-data-reports-with-r/</guid>
      <description>A lot of data analysts will find themselves doing repetitive manual tasks on a data set every day/week/month in Excel, then copying and pasting their updated pivot tables and charts into Word or PowerPoint reports for their stakeholders. If this sounds like your job description, you may want to consider switching to a programming language like R. Writing scripts will allow you to automate the majority of these processes; from importing your data all the way through to emailing your boss the final report.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Showcase App</title>
      <link>/portfolio/showcase/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/portfolio/showcase/</guid>
      <description>We built an app to showcase how we combine powerful data programming in R with modern user interfaces using the latest HTML, CSS and Javascript frameworks.
Features:
 TV Data Dashboard Sales Data Dashboard Automated Report Generator  get a report your twitter data by typing in your username!  Data Exporting Examples  Branded Chart Image Downloads Data downloads to CSV or Excel PowerPoint Chart Downloads - build a chart in the app and download it into a powerpoint template as a native chart object    Click on the image above to check it out!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UK Crime Mapping Tool</title>
      <link>/portfolio/crimewatch/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/portfolio/crimewatch/</guid>
      <description>This is an example of how we can &amp;lsquo;democratise&amp;rsquo; a data source by combining back-end data programming with a simple, effective user interface.
The application uses geocoding and GPS to allow users to retrieve and map data from the UK Police data base at a location of their choice within England, Wales or Northern Ireland.
Currently the app will return data for the most recent month available in the data base (March 2018 at the time of writing).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multivariate Dot-Density Maps in R with sf &amp; ggplot2</title>
      <link>/blog/2018/05/02/2018-04-08-multivariate-dot-density-maps-in-r-with-sf-ggplot2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2018/05/02/2018-04-08-multivariate-dot-density-maps-in-r-with-sf-ggplot2/</guid>
      <description>Background Last June I did a blog post about building dot-denisty maps in R using UK Census data. It has proven to be a fairly popular post, most likely due to the maps looking like something you’re more likely to see in the Tate Modern…
Not only do these maps looks beautiful, but there is a strong argument that they do a better job of representing data compared to the more common choropleth methods of filling geographical regions with one colour based on one variable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exterion Media Work Shop Play Dashboard</title>
      <link>/portfolio/workshopplay/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/portfolio/workshopplay/</guid>
      <description>We&amp;rsquo;ve just re-built Exterion Media&amp;rsquo;s Work Shop Play survey dashboard! The dashboard is updated monthly with 3-4 new surveys across a variety of topics of relevance to the &amp;lsquo;Work.Shop.Play Urban Community&amp;rsquo; and has the following features built in:
 A reactive front-end design with compatibility across all device platforms: Desktop, Tablet &amp;amp; Mobile Interactive user inputs to compare survey responses across a wide range of demographic target groups Branded chart image exports and data exports to CSV or Excel  Click on the image above to check it out!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Crypto Currency Tracking Tool</title>
      <link>/portfolio/cryptotracker/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/portfolio/cryptotracker/</guid>
      <description>A light-weight tracker tool built with R flexdashboard that scrapes crypto currency price data every hour and has interactive user inputs for personalised metrics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Responsive iframes for Shiny Apps</title>
      <link>/blog/2018/03/15/2018-03-15-responsive-iframes-for-shiny-apps/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2018/03/15/2018-03-15-responsive-iframes-for-shiny-apps/</guid>
      <description>Getting Shiny out into the wild Shiny has really changed game in terms of analytical web-application development. Anyone with a solid grasp of R programming and some basic HTML + CSS knowledge can get production quality apps and dashboards up and running in days rather than months, and be in complete control of the process yourself. Furthermore, because it&amp;rsquo;s all open-source software, you have total ownership of the product you build - unlike many expensive off-the-shelf GUI solutions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interactive UK Election Dot Density Map</title>
      <link>/portfolio/dotmap/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/portfolio/dotmap/</guid>
      <description>Shiny App that visualises the density of electoral votes for each party in 2017 and 2015 General Elections as well as the EU Referendum.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Antivia Decision-Point Dashboard Catalog</title>
      <link>/portfolio/antivia/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/portfolio/antivia/</guid>
      <description>Use username: culture password: insight to log into our public Decision-Point catalog and check out some of our example dashboards.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Map your Google Location Data with R Shiny</title>
      <link>/blog/2018/01/31/2018-01-31-map-your-google-location-data-with-r-shiny/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2018/01/31/2018-01-31-map-your-google-location-data-with-r-shiny/</guid>
      <description>I Know What You Vizzed Last Summer  tl;dr click the image to launch the app
I guess I’m of that school of thought, I don’t mind my mobile tracking me.
As long as I don’t go breaking the law, or tweeting an ill-advised truth about a politician, it’s unlikely that anyone will be typing the Google Location of my front room into a cruise missile control unit. But I confess a stirring of nerves when I decided to map my own Google Location data using R’s Leaflet package.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Visualising Intersecting Sets Of Twitter Followers</title>
      <link>/blog/2018/01/25/2018-01-25-visualising-twitter-follower-overlap/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2018/01/25/2018-01-25-visualising-twitter-follower-overlap/</guid>
      <description>Twitter AnalyticsThere has been a surge in a lot of great twitter analytics recently in the #rstats world, in part due to Michael Kearney’s excellent rtweet package. It makes wrangling with the twitter API like water off a duck’s back (twitter, bird, duck? sorry). You almost feel like some sort of Zuckerberg-esque data tycoon when you realise the amount of data you can access with a few lines of code.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building a Cryptocurrency Tracker with R</title>
      <link>/blog/2018/01/22/2018-01-22-building-a-cryptocurrency-tracker-with-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2018/01/22/2018-01-22-building-a-cryptocurrency-tracker-with-r/</guid>
      <description>TL;DR - check the tracker out here. 
As a recent cryptocurrency &amp;lsquo;Investor&amp;rsquo; (0.13 ETH baby) I wanted to build a light tracker tool that could help me keep up with the mad market volatility in a more personalised manner.
Of course, there&amp;rsquo;s no better tool for this task than the open-source programming language R, and the multitude of packages built for it that allows programmers with very modest levels of front-end development and sys-admin knowledge to go from nada to fully deployed, production quality web-application in a few hours.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Migrating from Xcelsius Dashboards on a Budget</title>
      <link>/blog/2018/01/17/2018-01-17-migrating-from-xcelsius-dashboards-on-a-budget/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2018/01/17/2018-01-17-migrating-from-xcelsius-dashboards-on-a-budget/</guid>
      <description>The Death of Flash SAP XCelsius was the Ford Fiesta of the BI industry. Inexpensive to run, simple to implement. Businesses could get dashboards up and running in days or hours. We’ve helped clients design over 1,000 XCelsius dashboards over time, so we know how practical and adaptable they were.
But then the industry went and killed Flash. Old XCelsius dashboards, which worked perfectly well last month and posed no threat to anyone’s IT security, are now downloaded and treated as high-risk by browsers, or blocked outright.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reproducible Shiny App Development with Modules</title>
      <link>/blog/2018/01/05/2017-11-13-reproducible-shiny-app-development-with-modules/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2018/01/05/2017-11-13-reproducible-shiny-app-development-with-modules/</guid>
      <description>Happy New Year to one and all!
As data scientists/analysts/researchers/programmers/anything else on that crazy data science Venn diagram, I’m assuming all of our new years resolutions involve visualising our data with more sophistication and finesse. So with that in mind, I thought it was high time for a post about the joys of modularizing your shiny app code.
New Year, new improved workflows with emphasis on efficiency &amp;amp; reproducibility, amiright?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Market Research Can Tidy Up</title>
      <link>/blog/2017/10/12/2017-10-12-how-market-research-can-tidy-up/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2017/10/12/2017-10-12-how-market-research-can-tidy-up/</guid>
      <description>Synopsis Market Research is great at compiling the right data, but not so good at making it easy to use. This isn’t about “storytelling”. It’s about the data itself, and clarity on what delivering it actually means. Getting the data out of siloes like tabs and SPSS where it cannot adequately be mined, and out into the big wide world as Tidy Data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>When It Rains, It Pours</title>
      <link>/blog/2017/10/03/2017-09-20-when-it-rains-it-pours/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2017/10/03/2017-09-20-when-it-rains-it-pours/</guid>
      <description>A Dive Into Some Global Flooding Data I always like to keep a look out for interesting open data sets. One great resource for such things is Jeremy Singer-Vine’s Data is Plural weekly newsletter that brings together a collection of “useful, curious datasets” for us all to enjoy and wrangle with.
One that cropped up last week was The Dartmouth Flood Observatory’s Global Archive of Large Flood Events.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/contact/</guid>
      <description>How can we help? We like to talk to people about how make the most of their data. Whether you think you could benefit from some data cleaning or process automation, a bespoke web-interface to connect you to your insights, or training to take your own data skills to the next level - get in touch below and we&amp;rsquo;ll get back to you as soon as possible.
If you already have an idea for a particular tool, dashboard or any other data application that you would like developed, fill out this form to give us an understanding of what you&amp;rsquo;re looking for and we&amp;rsquo;ll get back to you with a proposal.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FAQ</title>
      <link>/faq/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/faq/</guid>
      <description>What’s an app? What’s a portal? Security, users and logins GDPR What kind of data can we put in? How do we add data? What technology do we use? How do users access the data they need? How are the apps and portals hosted and accessed? How do you track usage? How are projects managed? How much do projects cost? Other questions?   What’s an app? By Apps, we mean online, responsive visualisation tools created with data on one topic.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Our Tech Stack</title>
      <link>/tech/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/tech/</guid>
      <description>Why we use open-source We&amp;rsquo;re passionate about using open-source software (OSS) to develop specialised data solutions and tools for our clients. The benefits of using OSS as opposed to pre-packaged products are numerous; the most obvious two being flexibility and cost. We benefit from the rich ecosystem of open-source tech that we can bring together into a product that works for you. And you don&amp;rsquo;t pay extortionate per-user licencing costs!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Transform Your Data Skills</title>
      <link>/training/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/training/</guid>
      <description>In many sectors and industries data has become the most valuable resource a business can acquire. As the the volume of data keeps getting bigger, having the tools to harness it for insight is vital. Manipulating large quantities of data in programs like Excel can be inefficient, frustrating and error-prone.
For this reason, more and more people are switching to programming languages like R for data tasks.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>