<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Shiny on Culture of Insight</title>
    <link>/tags/shiny/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Shiny on Culture of Insight</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018 Culture of Insight. All Rights Reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 15 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/shiny/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Responsive iframes for Shiny Apps</title>
      <link>/blog/2018/03/15/2018-03-15-responsive-iframes-for-shiny-apps/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2018/03/15/2018-03-15-responsive-iframes-for-shiny-apps/</guid>
      <description>Getting Shiny out into the wild Shiny has really changed game in terms of analytical web-application development. It allows analysts, researchers, scientists, or anyone who has a solid grasp of R programming to build their own highly bespoke web-apps to explore and communicate their data, without having to employ the help of front-end developers or data engineers. You can get production quality apps and dashboards up and running in days rather than months, and be in complete control of the process yourself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Map your Google Location Data with R Shiny</title>
      <link>/blog/2018/01/31/2018-01-31-map-your-google-location-data-with-r-shiny/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2018/01/31/2018-01-31-map-your-google-location-data-with-r-shiny/</guid>
      <description>I Know What You Vizzed Last Summer  tl;dr click the image to launch the app
I guess I’m of that school of thought, I don’t mind my mobile tracking me.
As long as I don’t go breaking the law, or tweeting an ill-advised truth about a politician, it’s unlikely that anyone will be typing the Google Location of my front room into a cruise missile control unit. But I confess a stirring of nerves when I decided to map my own Google Location data using R’s Leaflet package.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building a Cryptocurrency Tracker with R</title>
      <link>/blog/2018/01/22/2018-01-22-building-a-cryptocurrency-tracker-with-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2018/01/22/2018-01-22-building-a-cryptocurrency-tracker-with-r/</guid>
      <description>TL;DR - check the tracker out here. 
As a recent cryptocurrency &amp;lsquo;Investor&amp;rsquo; (0.13 ETH baby) I wanted to build a light tracker tool that could help me keep up with the mad market volatility in a more personalised manner.
Of course, there&amp;rsquo;s no better tool for this task than the open-source programming language R, and the multitude of packages built for it that allows programmers with very modest levels of front-end development and sys-admin knowledge to go from nada to fully deployed, production quality web-application in a few hours.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Migrating from Xcelsius Dashboards on a Budget</title>
      <link>/blog/2018/01/17/2018-01-17-migrating-from-xcelsius-dashboards-on-a-budget/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2018/01/17/2018-01-17-migrating-from-xcelsius-dashboards-on-a-budget/</guid>
      <description>The Death of Flash SAP XCelsius was the Ford Fiesta of the BI industry. Inexpensive to run, simple to implement. Businesses could get dashboards up and running in days or hours. We’ve helped clients design over 1,000 XCelsius dashboards over time, so we know how practical and adaptable they were.
But then the industry went and killed Flash. Old XCelsius dashboards, which worked perfectly well last month and posed no threat to anyone’s IT security, are now downloaded and treated as high-risk by browsers, or blocked outright.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reproducible Shiny App Development with Modules</title>
      <link>/blog/2018/01/05/2017-11-13-reproducible-shiny-app-development-with-modules/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2018/01/05/2017-11-13-reproducible-shiny-app-development-with-modules/</guid>
      <description>Happy New Year to one and all!
As data scientists/analysts/researchers/programmers/anything else on that crazy data science Venn diagram, I’m assuming all of our new years resolutions involve visualising our data with more sophistication and finesse. So with that in mind, I thought it was high time for a post about the joys of modularizing your shiny app code.
New Year, new improved workflows with emphasis on efficiency &amp;amp; reproducibility, amiright?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>